翻译：桌面王(Netpilot)
特遣队：德语
Sonderkommando: German word.
该词汇用于二战集中营
Term used in the concentration camps
特指犯人的特殊身份
to designate prisoners special status
也被称为“秘密遣送者”
also called "secret carriers" .
这些特遣队员和其他集中营里的犯人有所不同
The members of a Sonderkommando are separated from the rest of the camp.
他们通常在工作几个月后被杀
They are killed after a few months of work.
走吧
Let's go.
停下！
Halt!
我们需要像你们这样的人在车间里工作
We need people like you in the workshops.
你们只要工作就有报酬
You will work and you will be well paid.
淋浴之后，直接到我这里来
After showering and soup, come directly to me.
我们需要护士
We need nurses.
我们需要各行各业的技工
We need artisans of all trades.
木工，工匠
Joiners, carpenters,
瓦工，建筑工
masons, concrete workers,
机械师，锁匠，电工
mechanics, locksmiths, electricians.
准备好了就来找我
When you're ready, come find me.
衣服都放这里
All clothes are here.
行李也是
All suitcases too.
脱下衣服
Undress.
快一点！ 记住你的编号
A little bit faster! Remember your hook number.
快点，汤快凉了
Hurry up, will cool the soup.
把门打开
Open the door.
怎么回事？
What is happening here?
谢谢！ 继续，关上门
Thank you! Go ahead. Close the door.
关门！
The door!
你过来
You too, come.
索尔之子
THE SON OF SAUL
快点
Faster.
快点干活
Come on, faster.
干活去
At work.
你！
You!
查查看！ 放那边
On checkout! Put it on this fund there.
他还有呼吸！
He's still breathing.
回去工作！
Get back to work!
好的，准备解剖
Good. Open it.
我只见过一次
I only saw it once.
这个女孩儿...
This girl...
他要验尸
He wants an autopsy.
把他带过去
Bring him to me.
- 我来 - 什么？
- Me. - What?
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
放到那里
Put it there.
放下吧，快点
Put it down. Right now.
医生，求你了...
Doctor, please ...
你是匈牙利人？
You're Hungarian?
我不知道
I did not know.
别解剖这个孩子
Do not open that boy.
放过他吧
Leave it as it is.
不行
No.
出去
Get out.
是你的孩子？
It's one of yours?
不管怎样
Whatever.
你已经不需要了
You did not need.
尽管如此
But your head, though!
你从哪儿来？
Where do you come from?
乌日霍罗德
Ungvár.
我和你一样是个犯人
I am a prisoner, like you.
你今晚有五分钟时间可以和他在一起
You'll have five minutes with him tonight.
但最终，他还是要和其他人一样被焚烧
But in the end, he will burn with others.
你叫什么？
What's your name?
奥斯伦德尔
Auslander.
索尔
Saul.
通通烧掉！
Burn the pieces!
- 在哪儿？ - 什么？
- Where? - What?
最后来的运送队？ 匈牙利？
The last convoy? Hungary?
回去工作！
Back to work!
你！
You!
是匈牙利人吗？
Hungarian?
- 谁？ - 运送队
- Who? - The convoy.
不是
No.
也许吧
Perhaps.
他们来自另外一个集中营
They came from another camp.
你！
You!
你朋友让你闭嘴
Your boyfriend is asked to close his mouth.
亚伯拉罕
Abraham!
给我金子
Bring me the gold.
但是...
But...
把报告给我！
Bring me reports!
别瞎说
Do not shit.
我想帮助你
I will help you.
回去工作！
Get back to work!
没有食物，要金子
No food. Than gold.
你在找什么？
What are you looking for?
金子，珠宝，贵重物品放到箱子里
Gold, jewels, valuables:in the box.
钱...你找到了什么
Money, money ... What you find.
要金子，我说！
Than gold, I said!
你想要偷东西吗，臭猪！
You want to put yourself in their pockets, dirty pig?
给我！
Give me that!
你和我，永远在一起
You and me, it's forever.
我们在这里4个月了...
Four months we are there ...
像家人一样！
like family!
去洗洗吧，你这个臭家伙
Go wash, you stink.
冷静
Calm down.
犹太教士...
Rabbi ...
要埋葬个人
Bury someone.
埋葬？念念祷告文不就行了
Bury? The prayer is enough.
我有尸体，帮帮我！
I have the body. Help me!
离开那儿，你懂犹太教祈祷词？
Get rid thee. You know the Kaddish?
我懂，他叫什么名字？
I'll say. His name?
我们做不了太多
We can do nothing more.
不行！
Not enough!
你知道的
You know.
你在我地盘干什么？
What are you doing in my Kommando?
你知道的！
You know!
- 你？ - 工人！
- You? - A work!
什么情况？
What's the matter?
- 他们不是这里的 - 我会送他们回去的
- they not be there. - I'll have sent them.
- 我不想这样，这是我的地盘 - 我是负责人
- I do not want. This is my Kommando. - I am Oberkapo!
你是个肮脏的犹太老鼠！
You're a dirty Jew rat!
- 他觉得我们搞砸了 - 不，没事的
- He feels we're screwed. - No, it's nothing.
还不够，他呢？
It's not much. And him?
我这没有
I have nothing.
- 你帮我找到纸了吗？ - 没有
- You found me paper? - No.
过来
Come.
快点！
Come on!
Quick!
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我需要一个犹太教士
I need another rabbi.
你为什么需要一个犹太教士？
You? Why you need a rabbi?
那还不够？
That by not enough?
犹太教士不会让你远离恐惧
A rabbi not save you from fear.
犹太教士？
A rabbi?
雅尼
And the Renegade?
你听说过雅尼吗？
You've heard of the Renegade?
希腊人，很显然他是个犹太教士
A Greek. Apparently he was a rabbi.
哪个营地的？
What Kommando?
米迪克营地
The Kommando Mietek.
事情做完了
The case is completed.
米迪克？
Mietek?
外面都是波兰蠢货
Outside. The Polish junk.
我认识他
I know him.
他手上有两块伤疤
It has two scars in FIG.
- 他怎么了？ - 伤疤
- He what? - Scars.
被上帝印上的
Marked by God.
迷信！
Superstition!
- 我要和他谈谈！ - 别说了！
- I need to talk to him. - Stopped!
快点干活！
Get me those parts!
他是我们一伙儿的
He is with us.
在卡纳有个女孩儿，她准备好了包裹
In Kanada, there is a girl. She package.
你能送人过去吗？
Can you send someone?
两天吧
In two days.
两天？
Two days?
他们已经在我们的名单上了
They are already our list.
谁告诉你的？
Who told you?
我在办公室的人说的
My guy in the office.
我们应该先拍照
We took the pictures first.
什么照片，希立亚？
What photos, Elijah?
没有时间了，我们要去那里
There was no time for that. We will go there.
你认为你自己能做任何事情了？
You think you can do everything explode?
你觉得你的照片能带来解放吗？
You think that your photos will come the liberators?
帮我找个锁匠
Find me a locksmith.
我可以
Me, I can.
- 你能做什么？ - 他要干什么
- You can what? - What he wants.
他在说什么？
What is he saying?
告诉他
Tell him.
- 你不知道我们在说什么 - 我该走了
- You do not know what we are talking. - I must leave.
他要个锁匠！
He wants a locksmith!
- 你会讲犹太话吗？  - 会几句吧
- You speak Yiddish? - Barely.
告诉他我是个钟表匠
Tell him that I was a watchmaker.
我会修理很多东西
I can fix everything.
他说他是个钟表匠，他会修锁
He said he was a watchmaker, he can do locksmith.
锁匠？
Locksmith?
跟我来吧
Come with me.
- 如果你过去就孤立了 - 来吧
- If you there going, you're all alone. - Come.
卡茨
Katz?
他们和我一起的
These two are with me.
进去吧
Go for it.
他们和我一起的
They are with me.
把他们烧掉！
Burn me these pieces!
我说了，这是犹太人的游戏！
I said, a play by Jew!
如果有囚犯头来，就给他们看
If a Kapo shows up.
- 米迪克...营地？ - 什么？
- Mietek ... Kommando? - What?
他怎么在这里？
Why is he here?
他在放哨
He stands guard.
比德曼
Biederman!
稍等
Wait here.
- 他是谁？ - 农场主
- Who is it? - The farm!
该死的米迪克！
Fucking Mietek!
修门，别瞎看！
Repair the door, but monitors!
你懂了吗？ 注意观察
You understand? Opens the eye.
你！
You!
完事了吗？
Finished?
这里烟太大了！
There's too much smoke!
你！
You!
这里烟太大了！
There's too much smoke!
你快点
Pushes you.
到外面去！
Go outside!
- 干什么？ - 到外面去
- What? - Go outside.
你去那儿？
Where you go?
停下！
Halt!
停下
Stop.
过来！
Come here!
锁匠！
Locksmith!
赶快完成！
Finish it!
集合！
Rally!
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
希腊犹太教士？
Greek rabbi?
小心扬灰！
Careful not to drop ashes!
你是雅尼？
You, Renegade?
我需要你
I need you
为了尸体
for the dead.
你明白吗？
You understand?
把骨灰都弄到水里去！
All ashes in the water!
孩子死了
Child death.
你是犹太教士！
You are rabbi!
米迪克知道你是犹太教士
Mietek knows you're a rabbi?
别停下！
Do not pull over!
把他们弄上来
Get them out of there.
原谅我
Forgive me.
谁能解释一下这是怎么回事？
Who can explain what happened?
你？
You?
我的铁锹...
My shovel ...
队长，他们这些臭猪不会讲德语
These pigs not speak German Oberscharführer.
有人能翻译一下...
Can anyone translate the ...
什么语言？
Which language?
匈牙利语
Hungarian.
匈牙利语！
Hungarian!
先生们
Gentlemen?
发生什么了？
What happened?
铁锹掉到水里去了
The shovel fell into the water.
他试图捞起它
He tried to catch her.
所以他救了...铁锹？
So she was rescued ... the shovel?
是的，队长！
Yes, Oberscharführer!
你看，他会讲德语
You see that he speaks German.
匈牙利语是很美丽的语言
Hungarian is a very beautiful language.
其他人待在这里
The other stays here.
让他们去工作！
Bring this pig to work!
快点！
Come on!
你是谁，混蛋？
Who are you, rot?
在我鞋里...
In my shoe ...
你要去哪儿？
Where you go?
比德曼营地
Kommando Biederman.
我会很快见到你的
I'll come see you soon.
快干活！
At work!
这个人是我营地的，给我吧
This one, it is my crema. I took him.
集合！
Call!
怎么样了？
What happened?
你找到希腊人了？
Did you find the Greek!
排队
In ranks!
脱帽
Hats!
你去哪儿？
Where you go?
我有事儿要做
I have stuff to do.
我和你一起去
I come with you.
不值得
Not worth it.
你来这里是要干什么？
What is the reason for your visit, please?
打扫
Clean.
打扫？
Clean?
打扫
Clean.
犹太人小村落的舞蹈，就像以前一样！
A small dance shtetl, like the old days!
出去！
Outside!
房间
Rooms
尸体解剖室...
the autopsy room ...
在哪儿？
Where are they?
你是白班的
you're of the day shift.
出去！
Out!
医生允许的
The doctor promised.
什么？
What?
你想被烧死吗？
You want to go up in smoke?
是黄金
Rate gold.
快点，给
Come on, give.
盛赞的你，主啊，宇宙的王者
Praised are You, O Lord, King of the universe,
给地球带来活力的人...
who make spring the bread from the earth ...
死亡天使听到了你的祈祷，犹太教士
The Angel of Death hears your prayers, Rabbi!
你，金子
You. Goldtone.
我没有
I have nothing.
你必须有啊，在你的床垫里或是袜子里
You necessarily have to, in your mattress or in a sock.
亚伯拉罕
Abraham!
记上吧
Account.
你下去干嘛了？
What did you do down there?
感恩
Given.
我说，给我
Give, I said.
我要拿到它们
I take them.
你记上吧
Account, you.
我们需要它们
We need them.
我们不能等待
We can not wait.
我们必须取回埃拉的包裹
We must retrieve the package Ella.
那些足够给卫兵了？
That will be enough for the guards?
是的
Yes.
那个屠夫想干嘛？
He wants what, the butcher?
孩子呢！
The boy!
孩子哪里去了？
Where is the boy?
我藏起来了
I hid it.
这样医生就看不见了
So that doctors do not see it.
你不会给替换了吧？
You can not exchange it?
用另外一个？
Take another one?
不会的
No.
我有验尸报告所有的一切
I have an autopsy and document everything.
过来
Come.
你叫什么名字来着？
What's your name again?
奥斯伦德尔
Auslander.
这里是尸体解剖室
It is in the autopsy room.
我一会儿回来
I come again.
这是什么？
What is it?
带走！
Bring it!
你在拿我们的生命开玩笑
You're playing with our lives.
我可以告诉德国人你在营地什么地方埋了你的书稿
I can show the Germans where you buried your writings on the camp!
我们今晚会得到另一批武器，准备明早行动
We get other weapons tonight. Be ready tomorrow morning.
早上？
The morning?
是的，这就是计划
Yes. That's the plan.
我要找犹太教士
I have to find a rabbi.
我以后会帮你找的
I find you after.
我们需要你
I'm going to need you.
你以前对我不感兴趣啊
You're not interested in me before.
一直没变过
It has not changed.
我要吃饭
I have to eat.
这不仅是他的尸体，是他审视我的方式
It was not only his body, it was his way of looking at me.
我要和他谈谈，太让人激动了
I had to talk to him. It was breathtaking.
是她自找的！
Then she asked for it!
我宁愿不理解
I would prefer not to understand.
你以前也谈论女性的
You also talking about women before.
我不记得了
I do not remember.
过来
Come.
我们没看见烟雾，他挡住了镜头
We saw nothing with smoke, he hid the camera.
你会开枪吗？
You know how to use a gun?
不会吧
Not really.
我教你
I will show you.
他不会开枪
He knows not to fight.
他今天救了我们，别抱怨了
He saved us today. Stop the hatching.
卡车来了
Trucks.
亚伯拉罕
Abraham!
运送队
A convoy.
很意外啊？
It was expected?
他们没告诉我
They told me nothing.
囚犯头
Kapos!
所有的囚犯头
All Kapos!
你，跟我来
You, come with me.
你和我在一起了
you're with me now.
快点，咖啡快凉了
Hurry up, the coffee will cool.
在室内消毒！
Indoor disinfection!
过来
Come.
快点！
Rally!
待在这儿
Stay here.
脱下帽子
Hats!
队长
Oberscharführer!
带领白班的人赶快工作
Bring the day shift reinforcements and put them to work.
遵命，队长
Yes, Oberscharführer.
之后，看看还有多少需要处理的
After, will see how much is left to be processed.
遵命，队长
Yes, Oberscharführer.
你过来
You, you got.
你也过来
You too!
收拾
Clean.
收拾桌子！
Table!
队长
Oberscharführer!
怎样了？
So?
还有多少要处理的？
How much is left to deal with?
- 米迪克，队长 - 几千人？
- Mille, Oberscharführer. - Thousand?
几千人...
Thousand...
我们晚上已经计划三次了
We expect three times that night.
要这样做：
So let's do it like this:
我们在黎明前必须完成
we must have finished at dawn.
每次2个男人，1个女人和1个孩子
At each passage, 2 men, 1 woman 1 child.
清空所有骨灰，暴露在空气中12分钟
Empty the ashes 1 both 2, aerate all 12 min.
是你的尽责，明白吗？
You are responsible. Including?
遵命，队长
Yes, Oberscharführer.
你完成后，清理并且消毒
When you finish, cleaning and disinfection
为接下来的事情做准备
for the upcoming treatments. Break.
笨蛋
Oberkapo!
遵命，队长
Yes, Oberscharführer?
我需要一个70人的名单
I need a list of 70 names.
男人，随便谁都行
Men which you can do without.
开始吧
Begin.
乐意效劳
At your service.
嘿，你！
Hey, you!
去厨房给我拿点吃的
Go in the kitchen and bring me Schlojme.
乐意效劳
At your service.
队长叫你呢
The Oberscharführer calling you.
嘿，你！
Hey you!
你待在这儿
You stay here.
使劲推！
Get moving or cramerez you all!
一群蠢货！
Bunch of crap!
他是我的人
This one comes with me.
去死吧！
Jump into the furnace going!
这个凉水不能喝
This cold water is not potable.
洗澡之后，你们会有茶水喝的
After the shower, you will have tea.
亚伯拉罕
Abraham!
你是对的，轮到我们了
You were right. It's our turn.
他明天要一个70人的名单
He wants 70 names tomorrow.
- 谁负责去拿包裹？ - 我
- Who will pick the package? - Me.
我来吧，埃拉认识我
I come. Ella knows me.
不，你要留在这里
No. You must stay here.
带上索尔，她认识
So take Saul. She knows.
我不认识啊
I not know.
但是如果
But if.
我要去那里
I want to go there.
索尔
Saul!
我和你说过什么
Do what I tell you.
和我一起的
It goes with you.
怎么了？
What is happening?
没事
Nothing.
他们俩和你一起去
They both go with you.
前进
Forward!
囚犯头
Oberkapo!
停下
Halt!
请指示，长官
Yes, Oberscharführer?
你干什么呢？ 我要你在这里！
What are you doing? We need you here!
我的人没法继续干活了
My men can no longer work.
这里有衣服要送去
There are clothes to the ceiling.
我们必须把它们送到仓库去
We must put them to the warehouse.
你待在这里，其他人去吧
You stay here. Others go there.
遵命，长官
Yes, Oberscharführer!
前进
Forward!
女孩儿的名字？
The name of the girl?
弗里德 埃拉
Fried, Ella.
弗里德
Fried!
手拿开
Hands off.
索尔
Saul!
你挺快的啊
You're fast, you.
你拿到了吗？
You have it?
是的
Yes.
- 他们要去哪儿？ - 去矿井
- They go where? - In the pits.
熔炉要满了
Furnaces should be full.
你去哪儿？
Where you go?
起开！
Leave me!
你是犹太教士？
You are rabbi?
你...
You...
你认识犹太教士吗？
You know a rabbi?
你是犹太教士吗？
You, Rabbi?
犹太教士？
Rabbi?
那里有犹太教士！
There, a rabbi!
犹太教士！
Rabbi!
过来
Come.
脱下衣服！
Undress!
快点！
Faster!
快讲话！
person to speak!
你去哪儿？
You're there, you?
带这个男人去特遣队
strong man to Sonderkommando.
你想被替换？
You already want to replace you?
告诉他！带这个男人去特遣队
Tell him! strong man to Sonderkommando.
你会丧命的
You lost your head?
什么？
What?
他们会杀了你的！
They'll kill you!
犹太教士
Rabbi?
看，犹太人，那就是下场
See, Jews, that's how it goes.
穿上那个
Take that one.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
特遣队
Sonderkommando!
别杀他，他是特遣队的
Do not kill him, it is the Sonderkommando.
我也是特遣队的
I too Sonderkommando.
闭嘴，犹太猪！
Shut up, Jew!
你是特遣队员，傻瓜！
You're a Kommando, dirty shit!
7005.
特遣队
Sonderkommando.
是特遣队的
It is the Sonderkommando.
这次，会把你双手都铐起来！
This time, it will do you two bracelets!
快点
Come on!
囚犯头
Oberkapo!
你要帮我的孩子下葬
You gonna help me bury my son.
67人
Sixty seven.
67人？
Sixty seven?
这是什么意思，混蛋？
What does that mean, motherfuckers band?
他是谁？
Who's that one?
另一个营地的
It is another crematorium.
比德曼营地
Biederman ahead.
操
Fuck.
囚犯头，为什么人数不对？
Kapo, why do not we have the right account?
队长，我们在混乱中失去了几个人
Oberscharführer, we lost men in the fire.
我们要清理一下
We'll see the call.
注意...
Warning...
前进
Market!
为什么把他带来？
Why you brought him here, that one?
犹太教士
Rabbi.
为了死去的人
For the dead.
我们也会死的，我们要照看自己
Our dead, we take care of ourselves.
人们过来看我
People come to see me.
我也来看你！
I came to see you!
我是在说祈祷词
I said kaddish.
他是犹太教士？ 他只是个留胡子的小偷而已！
A rabbi him? He's a thief with a beard!
孩子呢
That the child.
我藏起来了
I hid it.
你告诉我该怎么做
You tell me what to do.
索尔
Saul!
你晚上去哪儿了？
Where you been all night?
我去矿井了
I was taken to the pits.
包裹呢？
And the package?
那女人给你的包裹呢？
The women's package?
火药！ 你怎么能没拿来呢？
The powder! How does all jump without it?
弄掉了
It fell.
这就是你找到的？
That's what did you find?
他明天能帮助我们
It will help us tomorrow.
你去为死人寻找犹太教士？
Have you been searching for a rabbi to the dead?
包裹呢？
The packet?
他弄掉了
He lost it.
犹太猪！
Jewish shit!
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
他是谁？
Who is it?
我的儿子
My son.
但是你没有儿子啊
But you got no son.
有
Yes.
我要埋葬他
I have to bury him.
你不需要犹太教士
You do not need a rabbi for that.
至少他们需要，497个人
At least it will you need. four hundred ninety seven
他待在这里，把尸体弄走
Him, he stays here. Get rid of the body.
犹太教士
Rabbi!
挖！
Dig!
那是什么？
What is that?
克勒兹不在
Creuse not here.
我不知道
I do not understand.
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
这是我的地盘
This is my place.
清楚吗
Clear.
我说快走！
Get out, I tell you!
过来！快点！
Come! Quick!
- 他写了名单？ - 有多少人？
- He made his list? - How many men?
我们不能在等待了
We can no longer afford to wait.
那可不容易啊
The crema 2 not move a finger.
看看现在
And now this.
犹太教士？是安息日
So Rabbi? This is Shabbat.
你不知道？
You do not know about?
- 别烦他 - 你要干嘛？
- Leave him alone. - What do you want?
如果他真的是犹太教士，他应该开始祈祷
If he is really rabbi, he should start the prayer.
- 我们会因为你们两个被杀的 - 我们已经是死人了
- We will die because of you two. - We are already dead.
我要照看我的儿子
I have to take care of my son.
她不是我的妻子
It is not my wife.
你最后一次见到了？
You saw it when was the last time?
你没有儿子
You're no son.
你
You!
出去
Outside!
去找个孩子
Find me a boy.
同样的年龄，同样的头发
Same age, same hair.
你是抛弃生命去寻死
You have forsaken the living for the dead.
注意
Warning!
去更衣室
In the changing room!
干活
At work!
收拾衣服
Gather clothing.
- 另一个特遣队员 - 卫兵把他们焚烧了
- Another Kommando! - The guards burned them.
他在比德曼！
It was at Biederman!
犹太教士
Rabbi!
过来，混蛋！
Come here, you bastard!
快点，你要去战斗
Hurry up. You're going to fight.
快走，混蛋！
Advance, son of a bitch!
正像我说的，帮帮他自己吧
Like I brought, help yourself to him.
让我走吧
Let me go.
你
You!
犹太教士
Rabbi!
念祈祷词啊
Say kaddish.
求你了，祈祷词！
Please. Kaddish!
赞美和神圣的...
Magnified and sanctified ...
是...
is...
成为...
be the...
别浪费时间了，快走！
Not waste time. Forward!
五分钟时间，赶快
Five minutes. We must continue.
两公里就可以穿越树林
Two kilometers through the woods.
我们会找到
We should find members
我们部队的人
of the Home Army.
他们会给我们武器的
They will give us weapons.
我们要战斗，苏联人已经占领了克拉科夫
We will fight. The Soviets are almost in Krakow.
否则，我们就去普什奇纳
Otherwise, we will go to Pszczyna.
他们有武器还有吃的
They have weapons. And eat.
你怎么找到他们？
How do you find them?
你只需躲起来，然后等待
You have to hide and wait.
不
No.
我们必须找到同路人一起战斗
We must find supporters and fight.